<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on rubz.dev</title>
    <link>http://rubzk.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on rubz.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 18:51:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://rubzk.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to tet through a Data interview Part 2</title>
      <link>http://rubzk.github.io/posts/how-to-get-through-data-interview-pt2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 18:51:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubzk.github.io/posts/how-to-get-through-data-interview-pt2/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with the series of posts that I am putting together about the selection processes in the world of data, I leave here this second part focused on the evaluations of statistics, programming and machine learning. Everything you are going to read is subject to a compilation of personal experiences, talks with colleagues and the Internet. There is no exact formula but I hope I can provide you with a skeleton of how the different parts are evaluated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get through a Data interview Part 1</title>
      <link>http://rubzk.github.io/posts/how-to-get-through-data-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:19:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubzk.github.io/posts/how-to-get-through-data-interview/</guid>
      <description>When I was a teenager I was very bad at studying, in high school there was not a year where I did not go to summer school and in general the habit of studying annoyed me. But years later, when I entered college, I realized that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that I hated studying, I hated what I believed back then to be studying. I used to think that studying was sitting down and reading the book or the summaries that I have written on the subject thousands of times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Spotify Playlist with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>http://rubzk.github.io/posts/creating-spotify-playlist-with-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 15:20:44 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubzk.github.io/posts/creating-spotify-playlist-with-ml/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered how companies or Apps do to recommend moderately successful content to what we are consuming? When I asked myself this question I thought that obviously they must have a lot of information about their products such as Mercado Libre or Amazon: Product categories, weight, our purchase and search history, which product is usually bought together with another and so we can continue thinking of variables that could help recommend a product to a potential buyer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Machine Learning for begginners</title>
      <link>http://rubzk.github.io/posts/intro-to-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 19:21:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rubzk.github.io/posts/intro-to-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Following advice from leaders in the world of DS (Data Science) in Argentina, I decided to look for an old notebook that I had made to practice and write a short article that may help someone understand what is done in data science or able to introduce someone who has not the slightest idea in basic concepts.
Summary What we are going to be doing throughout the post is through a dataset (Dataset) provided by one of the kaggle competitions, we are going to first carry out a brief analysis of the information we have and then carry out a predictive model that identifies according to certain variables that the data set has if the person survived or not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
